okay folks welcome back this teaching is
going to be specifically dealing with
implementing the Asian range alright
the Asian range notice it does not say
ICT Asian range I did not create this or
author this concept my first
introduction to it was from another
trader which I'll mention later on in
the presentation but what ICT concepts
are going to be used in this module
we're gonna be introducing the Asian
range I'm going to be defining what the
Asian range is in charts and I want to
teach you how to utilize it in bullish
conditions and how to utilize it in
bearish conditions all right introducing
the Asian range now what is the Asian
range well the price action prior to the
Frankfurt open or London opening can be
very indicative of the future intraday
price movement now when we have a
directional bias you can use this Asian
range to build or frame a context or
story line to the markets likely
intentions there is a stillness in price
many times right before the intraday
directional impulse price swing you look
at the chart here on the right this is
an Aussie dollar chart you can see that
there is a little shaded area right in
here and it's delineate 'add with the
gray shaded box and I've labeled it not
surprisingly the Asian range so this
little piece of price action okay I
actually learned about this from Chris
Laurie and I'll show you what I was
doing before I learned this so that way
you can see I already had a beat on what
price should be doing but when I first
saw him refer to it in his free
teachings he has a website Chris Laurie
comm it's changed and morphed a little
bit over time but folks that have gone
through his material didn't know who I'm
referring to they would not an agreement
that they would know what I'm saying is
true
he taught about the Asian range many
times in free teachings so it's not like
I'm taking anything away from him
in fact if you're not happy with what
you see in my content but you do want to
take some advice from someone that has
seen a lot of things out there
Chris Laurie has a lot of good price
action study and his methods while they
are not mine there's some similarities
to what Chris does but I'm going to show
you what I took away from him this is
the only thing I really learned from
Chris Laurie really but yeah that's not
to diminish his importance as a teacher
or what he knows I'm just saying that
this is what I gleaned from his material
I liked it because I was already
familiar with using consolidations in
certain periods of a training 24-hour
period if you take certain ranges you
can do some magical things with them and
I teach you that in the mentorship and
it goes well beyond what I've done in
YouTube videos over the past couple of
years
so what I liked about it was I've seen a
lot of context right away when I seen
how that the range is applied to the
chart so I will give you what I used to
do and how I used entry techniques to do
it so that way you have a little bit of
a takeaway you not only just talked
about the range itself but what we can
do with it and then I'll show you what
I've done with it to incorporate it now
I'm not teaching you everything I know
about this range and what I've done with
it over the last mmm ten years or so the
the implementation of it I think is
useful for a developing trader but there
has to be some context behind it the
range itself doesn't produce anything
magical but if you have a storyline
behind what price should be doing that
particular day it is unbelievably
helpful okay so let's define the Asian
range of work what is it that we can do
in our charts to make it up here and
draw attention to it well the range
begins at 7:00 p.m. New York time and it
ends at midnight New York time now
a special inclusion here Chris Laurie
had his Asian Range pushed beyond
midnight if my if memory serves me
correct I believe he had 12:30 a.m. and
to me the financial markets really begin
at midnight New York time and it
probably sounds pretty arrogant of a
gang like me being in the States but if
you just study what I'm teaching you
folks you'll see right away what I'm
telling you is the gospel as it relates
to intraday price actions only now
everything else might be something
different but as far as intraday price
action I think I've cornered the market
in intraday price action so the height
of the range is the highest high between
7:00 p.m. to midnight in New York time
to the lowest low between 7:00 p.m. and
midnight New York time the width of the
range is obviously the duration of 7:00
p.m. to midnight New York time so let's
take a look at this chart here and we'll
get a little bit closer zoom in on it
okay I'll cover some points here now
right away when you see this it probably
still doesn't give you any kind of
insight and that's fine but I'm gonna
build on it and show you how useful it
is but we're gonna build the model with
specific buy and sell conditions later
on in this video but for now take a look
at what you see here okay and kind of
like Burness in your mind your focus
should every single day be zeroed in on
7:00 p.m. New York and whatever that
time is on your broker's platform
whatever your charting platform or
package shows find out what time it is
at 7:00 p.m. New York time and then find
that same time on your charts that's
where you put a vertical line at and
that begins the asian session and then
five hours later it'll be midnight in
New York time put another vertical line
in and there's your Asian range defined
by the duration the highest high and the
lowest low is what we would use to frame
out the range now there's a lot of
Voodoo that you can do with this range
okay and again I'm not teaching it here
but believe me it can take you to the
highest
in the lowest pit of the day there's
some things you have to incorporate in
that and I teach that in the mentorship
but for now let's teach you a very
simple approach to how to use this and
when you can filter out trades and not
do anything that may end up taking a
loss if you do otherwise so let's take a
closer look and remove all of the
benefit of seeing the price action there
okay now we do have the benefit of
hindsight but nonetheless I want to kind
of build an understanding about what
this range does or at least my
interpretation of it now I was able to
see right away the importance of
utilizing it in my view on price action
during this range what's actually
happening is there's orders that are
coming in and they're stacking up above
the market and below the market relative
to that range and it's also building up
a market sentiment now this compression
of market participation starts to build
up closer and closer and closer until we
get to midnight in New York soon as we
cross over midnight time in New York we
are in fertile ground for price movement
we're going to assume that everyone in
this listening audience is familiar with
channels ok or trading ranges the idea
is above this range there's going to be
buy orders those buy odors are going to
act as breakout artists ok in other
words they are not astute to know how to
buy when it's a low price or technically
oversold without the use of indicators
so they just want to be buying on
strength and there's really nothing
inherently wrong about that if you know
what you're looking for but most traders
don't know what you're looking for and
they just go in any willy nilly and
entry based on breaking out above a know
high they'll buy that and view that as
strengths and I'll put the stop-loss
right below the low which would be here
short sellers would do the opposite they
would have their sell orders below this
range so any movement lower would
hopefully put them in a short position
and they would take the other
end of that range and put their
protective by stop so buyers that want
to break out above this consolidation
are going to buy want to stop with a
protective cell stop below the low
short sellers want to sell on a stop and
use a protective buy stop above the high
okay so the storyline is what are we
gonna do after midnight which is this
vertical line here
what's the storyline where are we going
to go my whole entire career has been
based on understanding dis phenomena and
it's been a more or less a pursuit of
excellence so I want to know with the
highest probability which side are they
gonna work on okay and what I mean by
that is are they going to try to put a
specific party of traders whether people
wish or bearish traders in on the wrong
side right before London creates what
the higher low of the day so the key is
and this is to take away so far in us
this is what should be even in your
notes right now is what you're looking
for what sets up the opportunity if you
will for the particular trading day is
if we have a very narrow consolidated
range between 7:00 p.m. and midnight or
what would be deemed as the Asian range
so if we have a very narrow
consolidation there that sets up a huge
possibility of the algorithm going into
a trending model okay so in other words
without going into IFTA and teaching
anything really about that the market
will seek the liquidity above or below
this range with a premise that it's
going to put them in the wrong side and
then it'll go the other way for the
remainder of the trading day
okay so let's take a look at how it can
utilize it in a bullish condition now
the periods when price is bullish we can
extend the age and range high and low
into the future when price returns back
to the Asian range high we can
anticipate institutional buying let's
take a look at that as an example here
we're going to assume that we have in
understanding our expectation if you
will that the Aussie dollar was bullish
for this particular day now if you want
to know what would blend well to coming
to that conclusion of being bullish if
you look at the daily chart you'll see
that there was a reason for the Aussie
dollar reached up to a equal high okay
and go down to a four hour or one hour
chart you'll see also that it's obvious
you can see it so far what we've shown
in the teachings in this series it's
been pretty obvious to know where the
liquidity is and that's what this whole
day was reaching for the buy stops above
equal high now again I want to take off
the Asian range and provide just a blank
chart okay and assume for a moment pre
my exposure okay to asian range this is
what I used to do okay this is how I
actually traded and I was doing this
since 1994 so you'll appreciate
hopefully the evolution if you will of
my understanding about how this whole
buying below the open when it's bullish
or selling above the open when it's
bearish all those ideas came from this
individual specific element that I'm
going to show you now I would have on my
chart a list of all kinds of indicators
okay so I'm gonna spare you all that but
if we just look at price actions as a
naked form of open high low and close it
can be rather
well confusing but if you look for
specific times of the day and specific
generic concepts or characteristics that
should manifest themselves then there's
a storyline that will start to develop
and you get this over the years many
times it's referred to as tapereading
many times it's referred to as gut
feeling or just triggers intuition or
just last I call it intuition and
experience if you will once you know
what you're looking for you wait for
that scenario to unfold so this is what
I would have done without the Asian
range this is how I always treated the
SP the bond market and currency futures
I would get the opening price at
midnight okay and that opening price is
seen here right there and all I do is
draw that opening price out all the way
out until 11 o'clock in the morning New
York time now the reason why I would
draw it out to 11 o'clock in the morning
New York time is because that would be
the end of the morning trend for the S&P
500 okay so that there's a reason for
that hour it's not that I'm just pulling
it number out of the air it's also very
close to what was taught in the previous
teaching the London close so that's what
makes that London close scenario it's
the end of the a.m. trend when the stock
market or equities market in the states
also it overlaps conveniently enough
with the close of London trading so
there's a little bit of manipulation
that goes on in there and some profit
taking so it creates an opportunity but
for opening range concepts I draw it out
to 11 o'clock in the morning New York
time okay so if we are looking for a
bullish scenario and I'm gonna just make
the case that we would be expecting a
higher Aussie dollar here I want to see
price initially drop down below that
opening price because I want to be
buying below the opening price the
understanding is is I want to figure out
what Larry Williams said he couldn't do
as a teacher I took it as a challenge as
a student that that's what I'm gonna
look for I'm gonna figure that out and
this is what my interpretation
of how to do that very thing was seen in
price action I would use the opening
price and as it dropped down
I would buy right there now if I either
did not have the guts to do that
or I missed the opportunity sometimes I
would wait for a specific price it
wouldn't get there and then it would
take off if I saw a reversal or
potential reversal I would look at the
high rate but right before the drop down
in here you can see there was a small
little segment of price action right
before that drop down I would put a buy
stop right there now as I graduated in
my understanding I would look to get in
as price was dropping down but I'd also
have this buy stop in place even if I
was able to get in many times price
would sometimes snap me in and put me in
own a buy stop and on my marker order as
price was dropping down so in other
words what I was doing was I was waiting
for price to drop down below this
horizontal line or a trend line segment
here okay that's delineating open price
at midnight in New York time the drop
down below that I'm hopefully trying to
buy that now as it starts to drop my eye
goes right here because now we're below
the opening price it may go lower and
give me my ultimate price of entry but
it may not so as soon as it starts to
break down after midnight and it goes
back to back down below the opening
price I immediately add a buy stop to
half the position I want to trade at
this point here so in other words if my
full position down here was say ten
standard Lots I would go in with a buy
stop at five standard Lots right here so
that way at worst case scenario if I
don't get my fill here and it reverses
if you will and runs real quick for
these highs it'll put me at least half
the position I wanted to get on down
here so half of something is better than
nothing if I were able to put on the
full position down here I would still
try to take
this stop-off if I get my full position
on down here sometimes I wasn't able to
do that now the problem is and your mind
is okay what happens if you put your
pole position down here and you're
risking 2% well I wasn't risking 2% so
I'm trading at 1% 1/2 percent and then
this position here if it fills me I'm
not over leverage or if I do get one
half percent on here and this half here
it would technically put me over
two-and-a-half percent risk but I'm
gonna be more aggressive about trying my
initial stop-loss up to try to pare that
down to 2% okay and that's really what I
was doing now let's contrast what I just
did here with the implementation of the
agent range and this is exactly where
price would fill you with that buy stop
being tripped so now I would be long
here if I didn't get filled down here
below the opening price at midnight this
would be where my buy stop with filming
and my stop loss would be below the low
and you can see I had to weather this
retracement here and then because he
gets the move later on in the day now
let's take this discussion back the
implementation of the Asian range and
I'll show you how I evolved and seen a
much clearer view on price action using
the range as I define it here 7 o'clock
p.m. New York time to midnight zero zero
level not like 12:30 or 1:00 o'clock in
the morning on that stuff exactly at
midnight ok because what we're banking
on is the midnight opening price that's
what sets the algorithm it goes through
it goes to a reset if basically if you
if you want to think of it like that so
if we're bullish it's going to go below
that opening price to seek liquidity and
then go higher and spend the rest of the
day going higher when it's bearish it'll
go above the opening price at midnight
to reach for liquidity and then move
lower for several hours going into
London closed or New York open so
let's take a look at what's going on
with the implementation of the agent
range now we have a tight asian range in
here okay and again by odors are above
the range sellers are below the range
price right after midnight does what
goes up and taps the asian range high
now you're saying okay well it didn't go
above it let your stop be there and I
guarantee you the broker spread will
open up wide enough to get that and
you'll be in long and your stop-loss
which will be right that low or just
below it will be tagged right there even
though it reflects here your broker and
this is what you sign up with when you
open up your account you are giving them
permission to open the spreads up on you
everybody makes this big complaint about
oh well they did this they did that you
sign it and you agree to it so when you
see people online saying a date rig with
three pip stop losses that's not true
it's not accurate and they are not doing
it with live accounts because believe me
in-house plenty money gains with the
brokers would eat them up immediately it
would not happen okay I think personally
with a stop loss of anything less than
10 pips is just ludicrous it's stupid
okay because Begley is from a retail
brokers standpoint you're inviting them
to take your stock it's just way it is
you can argue with me and give me all
kinds of track history and say well I'm
trading with a five pip stop here and
there it's fine
do it ten years and see how many times
get burned the point is why offer
yourself up on the altar for that
sacrifice when there's better ways of
doing it you don't have to have less
than 10 pip stop losses to do very well
we have an Asian range in here with the
understanding or in this model we're
gonna expect bullishness okay and price
starts to go up initially and comes back
down and breaks the asian range down
here so we take out the low on the asian
range that's been extended beyond
midnight that trips in sellers and it
also knocks out individuals that would
have been pulled in on a buy stop right
at this level so long holders are in and
now they're out short holders are in now
and their stop-loss is above here or
here so they're taking both sides of the
marketplace in and out and then the
market takes off goes higher what we
look for is this little movement right
here that movement is what sets the tone
when we're bullish we want to be buying
there or we can do what I showed earlier
you can put a buy stop right here if it
gets filled a contingent order that
would be if I'm filled with your broker
for cancer order basically if we have a
parent contingent order suggesting they
who buy on a stop if that stock gets
filled if it happens then we would place
a sell stop below this low at some
specific price level and you could leave
that in the marketplace and go to sleep
and don't even worry about watching all
this stuff okay that's one way you can
apply a day traders model and/or enter
with a long term model but using a day
traders approach to trading that whole
entry if you've missed this one okay and
price starts to rally away we have to
have the story line behind this example
of being bullish otherwise this could be
an easy sell as you'll see when we talk
about when the conditions are bearish
but knowing where the market is most
likely trying to go from a higher time
frame standpoint is significant and
crucial and utilization of the Asian
range otherwise you're just going to do
some things that aren't going to be
profitable so if we're bullish we'd like
to see this element here and then this
here no problem we don't need to get
that and we don't need to be a part of
this movie or okay we wouldn't wait for
price to come back down and touch the
Asian range high now it does so here
that's a little early and then we do it
again in the New York open so New York
open we see price trading back to the
Asian range high right there is where
institutional buying is going to step in
why are they doing that because the
initial range that was set between 7:00
p.m. and midnight
midnight is when HIPAA the interbank
price delivery algorithm resets and then
it it attacks
open liquidity or the open flow which
would be the order table of the agent
range and below the agent range all
right you know you're gonna know 15
different people that work at a bank or
they know somebody they smoke cigars
with on the weekends in the air market
maker they're gonna say what I just said
to you is nonsense but I'm telling you
they don't know what you're talking
about because I'm doing this daily to
the PIP week after week day after day
and I'm telling you it's not based on
anything else except for what I learned
okay and some of the things are gonna go
in the category of tinfoil hat and I'll
just let you wrestle with that I don't
really care about your opinion just know
that what I'm suggesting to you here if
you look at it in price action it's
there so we can see the optimal trade
entry from this low to this high retrace
back down New York open overlap with the
Asian range high with the story line is
that we're bullish on the higher time
frame beautiful illustration of a Asian
range application in bullish conditions
in an off to the races we go so we have
two opportunities in here in the New
York open and we have one set up here
that gives us a really really low and
entry point with very little risk in
terms of our entry and then the
subsequent move higher
the other portion would be entering on a
stop here above the Asian range but you
wait you have to sit up and you have to
wait for price to drop down below the
Asian range then you buy want to break
above the asian range high but the
conditions have to be bullish and we
have to first see Asian range low break
then a buy stock can be placed at the
Asian range high if you do this before
the Asian range low is taken you will
get burned you will get stopped out you
will send me email saying doesn't work
I'm telling you there's rules here and
it just gave them to you rewind the
video and listen to it again
it's very clear
all right say utilization of the Asian
range in bears conditions okay again
like we said but when it's bullish
there's a period it's quiet right before
the Frankfurt and London open and we
wouldn't focusing on that and when it's
in a tight narrow consolidation we're
gonna be looking for some measure of
manipulation if you will on price action
so what we're going to doing is waiting
for a break in the Asian range low and
then when price trades back up to it
we're going to be anticipating
institutional selling so let's take a
closer look at this example here
zoom in here get some more detail now
let this image burnin for a minute okay
and now we're going to take it off and
go to an element of naked price action
and I'm gonna show you what I was doing
prior to learning about the Asian range
there's the opening price again this
candle and I would be looking for
bearish price movement and if we're
going to just suspend your disbelief
whether or not I was actually bears
before this day or not trust me and go
through my Twitter you'll see all kinds
of examples of me doing this very thing
but nonetheless we're gonna sue for sake
of argument that we're bearish on this
particular currency that day okay we're
gonna be looking for price movement
above the opening price that's what I'm
looking for here okay now I learned
early on that these levels these double
tops they were fake outz and that's why
I loved the turtle soup trading pattern
that I learned in a book called street
smarts and if you don't have it you
should buy it's a very very good book
but that pattern in there resonated with
me because I was already doing things
similar to that and I would just look
for those equal highs and equal lows
which I've already taught you in this
series and right away there's a large
number of you in our community that are
just going through the roof right now
with excitement cuz now you see
something that's always been there but
now you see it and it's useful to you
you can see where price is drawn to well
if we see this time of day this is
midnight and we're bearish we have equal
highs in here right away I want to know
there's going to be a rally above the
opening price and I extend that out in
time about love o'clock in the morning
New York time and any time price trades
above that opening price and it's inside
of a kill zone that means the London or
New York open kill zone if it trades
above that opening price I will look to
go short now if we go above it and this
is what I was doing before I started
incorporating the Asian range concept I
would just simply look for this rally
above if I got this scenario here I was
selling right there
I would sell short the SP I would sell
short Deutschmark I would sell short the
Swiss franc I would swell the and all
those commodity futures contracts that's
what I would that was my entry technique
right there and then I would go to sleep
and wake up around 5 o'clock and more
and hopefully I'd get some profit and I
would take something off try my
stop-loss really really tight sometimes
get stopped out other times it would
carry right on over into Globex into
open outcry in the pits and then I would
catch some more follow-through in the
day session hours in the New York
session but if that's my entry point
there just like anybody else life may
get in the way I may get sick my kids
may be complaining about growing pains
and I can't be in front of my charts you
know this happens you know I'm a dad I'm
a husband I own - I'm a pet parent own
two boxers and anything can happen
okay the distract me from actually
getting in where I want to get in it I
don't always use limit orders there are
certain conditions where I want to use a
limit order but mainly I want to be
executing rate when the markets
happening to be trading against my
directional bias for the day I don't
mind market order some folks that say
you shouldn't be using market orders you
know they should be using limit orders
again that goes along with not knowing
what I do I'm actually trading
aggressively rate as the markets
screaming higher I go marketing selling
short rate than in there and you seen my
examples I'm getting in there rate to
highs and order very lows so I don't
care what anybody else's opinion is I
can do it over and over again you're not
repeatedly showing it week after week
if you are up in a week looking at lemon
you can use market orders but if I am
NOT going to be awake I will put a limit
order in about two pips above these
equal highs my limit order would be
about bear and my stop-loss will be
about 35 to 40 pips and I would go to
sleep and be comfortable with that ok I
would have an 80 pip take profit on the
full position that way if I did wake up
and it moved an accelerated pace and
move 80 pips that would be 5 pips over
my weekly objective which is 75 pips I'm
always aiming for fifty seventy five
pips only for a weekly objective once I
do that I'm done trading I don't do
anything else but I leave myself the
opportunity to catch a tiger by the tail
if I wake up and the markets already
moved 80 pips I'm done for the week and
I didn't do anything but sleep in the
whole process but if I miss this
opportunity okay if I miss it my eyes go
rate to the low that form prior to that
run above the opening price when I'm
bearish so I'm going to place a sell
stop to get me in now sell stops
gentlemen you understand them as a
protective basis or mechanism to protect
your long position if there is no long
position and you place a sell stop it's
going to put you in short and that's
what I'd be expecting to see happen here
so in price drops down I could be short
there and my stop-loss
would be above the high today so let's
assume for a moment that I missed this
opportunity here and I just can't stay
up something happens you know my wife is
getting ready have a baby this has
happened I had to take a trade so I'm
you know I have to trade folks okay it
is what it is okay and I had to hear
about it on the way to the hospital that
day but nonetheless you know this is
this is real-life stuff here folks so if
I miss the opportunity to get in okay
and and the Swiss franc is looking to go
lower I'm gonna place a sell stop a
little swing low right before the rally
above the opening price with the
expectation that if this order fails it
will place a protective buy stop above
the high + 3 pips and then again same
scenario I would
take profit of 50 tips which is a low
and I make weekly objective and that's
it I don't trail my stop
I do not trail stops I do not have a
mechanism that trails my stop-loss
slower because I don't think it should
be done okay
I teach taking partials is the better
way to go and leave your stop-loss where
you initially put it manage the risk
from taking partials and then slowly
move it down after New York trading
starts because if you're gonna get a big
grain today like we see here you want to
trail the stop-loss after New York has
done its retracement if we take the
conversation back to the utilization of
the Asian range we can see here what's
actually happening is we have a tight
narrow consolidation and we're bearish
now think we have folks that want to buy
on the breakout they get tripped in with
the move above the asian range high here
so now what are they they're long wears
their stuff lots gonna be at right below
that low mark goes right down below
there to take their stops notice it
doesn't just go a little bit it goes
conveniently 10 pips below it it's gonna
sweep out anybody that has a stop loss
at or just below that low and using that
little tail over here they think that
they're safe they're not the real move
is running above the asian range high
after the buys have been put in then
taken out driven back up again why
because short sellers that we're lucky
enough to try to sell short at the top
of this channel or trading range they're
making money here they're not going to
be allowed to be profitable they run on
their stops which would be a buy stop
run above these highs that's where
you're looking to be a seller this is
the lowest risk high probability entry
for using the Asian range if we wait for
the Asian range low to be broken
and it reads back up to it that's the
other entry point using the Asian range
so we can see there's two ways of using
this range selling above the Asian range
high when we're bearish best scenario
especially if you have the centering
that's been outlined here understand the
storyline you have to have a bias on the
day and do not change gears based on all
this little movement here you have to
stick to what your analysis is calling
for our time frame is going to go lower
so we want to be looking for the market
to take out the Asian range high if that
happens we could sell short there or the
low risk confirmation trade is wait for
the Asian range low the break and then
trade back up to it and then we can sell
there okay and if it happens to occur
during an ICT kill zone London open or
New York open their probabilities go
through the roof in terms of being well
accurate and then you can see that
unfolding your charts if you go through
the the charts with this in mind okay
just put the asian range on and paint
them manually I know you all want
indicators and pop this up and empty for
this and empty for that physically draw
them in spend some time in the charts
get intimate with price action because
it's going to teach you a lot more I had
to do this stuff with charts that were
you know drew hand-drawn like I I had
well session with printed charts so I
would print out charts and I would do
all these things by hand and a ruler and
a magic marker and highlighter that's
the stuff I used to do and then I'm
convinced that's what made me good at it
being lazy about this okay what you're
really saying is is I don't really have
time to really study it just give me the
lipstick on the chart and then there it
is you will not get the same level of
appreciation or understanding if you
short cut it draw the levels on as I
taught so by taking the time to draw
this out manually and reminding yourself
okay maybe even be worth taking the time
to type out a notation you know in this
in this area here
to not focus one two movements below the
age range okay focus primarily on a move
above the Asian range high when we're
bearish and/or if we break the low the
Asian range after midnight wait for a
retest uniform for resistance now think
about what you're seeing here if we look
at price action like this if what if we
don't use the asian range concept here
as i'm outlining the question is is why
would this be a selling point i mean
granted you know you can go back to this
low here and say well that's probably a
reason for it but would you really look
at that after seeing this and then this
movement through yeah without this in
sight chances are you're probably not
going to see this actual scenario and
that's just a difference between
understanding tape reading and building
context behind price and also sticking
with a bias it's important to know what
a trading bias is for any given day and
anyone that tells you don't trade with a
bias they're the ones that are telling
you that because they don't know how to
do it I've given many examples on how
you can arrive at a daily bias and
you're not gonna get a daily bias that's
accurate every single day so don't let
me paint that picture for you but I can
be in the upper 90s in terms of my
probabilities and directional bias if
you can get just 65 to 70 percent
accuracy with or with your bias and then
wait for conditions like I'm showing you
here adding time of day
kill zones daily bias focusing was the
Asian range we've already looked at
power three it builds the entire model
for the daily range and you are not
surprised when certain things happen in
fact you're anticipating them before
they happen and by seeing day after day
after day of doing this you become much
better at well interpreting price action
and forecasting which is a skill set
that you cannot learn from reading books
or watching my videos you have to spend
time in the charts and if you do that I
promise you you will glean more
that than anything else that you would
ever study I hope you enjoyed this
presentation and if you did you can find
more at the inner circle trader.com